# **SILAS JIMMY**

Nairobi, Kenya | +254 719 773 594 | <u>iimmysilas17@gmail.com</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a software developer who has been in the tech industry for three years now. My skills are versatile across the software development process and implementing fullstack applications. I develop user interfaces, design back-end architectures and enable a seamless communication between the front-end and back-end. I am a smart worker with a knack for finding solutions to problems as well as learning and using new technologies to boost user experience.

## **SKILLS**

Front-end development: HTML, CSS, Back-end development: Python, Nodejs,

JavaScript, Sass, Vuejs, Angular, Figma, Canva, Flask, SQL, NoSQL, Nestjs

Material design, Ant design

APIs: REST, WebSockets

Tools: VSCode, Github, SonarQube

Cloud Services: AWS, Firebase, MongoDB

**EDUCATION** 

Udacity Nanodegree, Cloud Developer

Remote/Online May 2022 - June 2022

Udacity Nanodegree, Python Programming

Remote/Online January 2022 - April 2022

Pwani University

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Kilifi, Kenya

September 2017 - December 2021

**EXPERIENCE** 

ConnectedLife Health Pte Singapore, Singapore
Fullstack Developer - Remote July 2024 - August 2024

Description

Incorporate configuration functionalities to the company's web dashboard used by the organisation's clients, i.e medical facilities, to enable the medical practitioners better monitor their patient's health and wellness.

Cyeco Africa Limited Kilifi, Kenya
Chief Marketing Officer March 2023 - August 2024

Description

Organise and oversee marketing strategies aiming to shape the company's brand and promote the company's products and services.

Google Apprenticeship Nairobi, Kenya
Fullstack Engineer January 2022 - April 2022

Description

Research project to find a tech solution that promotes good health and well being by implementing a web-based meal planning system. Developed a meal-planning app prototype that enables users to generate balanced diets and connect them to the nearest eateries in their current location.

# **PROJECTS**

Trivia API *May 2021 - June 2021* 

❖ A RESTful web application made to hold trivial subjects and play word games. Responsible for implementing API's endpoints, write test cases and design error-handling mechanisms for erroneous requests.

Technology: Python, React, Flask, Postgres

Link to project

## **Dema Planner**

January 2022 - April 2022

❖ A web-based meal planning system used to generate balanced diets from locally available foods and connect users to nearest eateries.

Technology: Sass, Vuejs, Firebase

Link to project

# Udagram

June 2021 - July 2021

❖ A cloud application that allows users to register and log in to a web client, post pictures and process them through an image filtering system.

Technology: Angular, Ionic, TypeScript,

Link to project

Sass, Node-Express, AWS

## **INTERESTS**

Programming, Problem solving, Data analysis, Research, Design, Art

#### **LANGUAGES**

English, Swahili, Spanish

#### **REFERENCES**

## Ike Mawira

Software Engineer

ConnectedLife Health Pte

+254 711 111915

**Pritthish Chattopadhyay** 

Data Scientist

ConnectedLife Health Pte

+44 7930 143897